<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[VTM-Velvet-Vale]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>VTM-Velvet-Vale</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:38:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:38:23 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title><description><![CDATA[Welcome to the Wiki for the Velvet Vale, a Modern day Vampire setting similar to such things as Vampire: The Masquerade.
<a data-href="Lucian Valemont" href="characters/lucian-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lucian Valemont</a> <br><a data-href="Terminology" href="information/terminology.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Terminology</a>
]]></description><link>welcome.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Welcome.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:36:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Rosethorn Pact]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Faction" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Faction">#Faction</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Rosethorn Pact is believed by most of <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a> to be a minor ideological splinter: an artistic, reformist circle tied loosely to <a data-href="The Velvet Court" href="organisations/vampire-clans/the-velvet-court.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Velvet Court</a>, advocating <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>–mortal harmony through culture and influence. Regents dismiss it as romantic posturing, dangerous only in rhetoric.<br>In truth, the Pact is an ancient covenant older than the Concord itself: a living ritual bound to an artifact known as <a data-href="The Obsidian Rose" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Obsidian Rose</a>, sustained by the blood and will of Thirteen Signatories, called the <a data-href="Thirteen Thorns" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thirteen Thorns</a>. Its purpose is not political reform, but transcendence.
<br>Beauty Is Communion: Art is the bridge between <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> and mortal soul. <br>Blood Remembers Love: <a data-href="Sanguis" href="information/sanguis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sanguis</a> carries memory beyond death. Unity Through Transcendence: Equality cannot be granted; it must be become. The Circle Must Be Complete: Thirteen voices, thirteen sacrifices, one bloom. <br>The Pact is governed by the <a data-href="Thirteen Thorns" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thirteen Thorns</a>, each holding one vote. Combined, these votes can: Subvert Concord edicts Stall or redirect Regent authority Enforce quiet blood-binding within court infrastructure To outsiders, this resembles a shadow tribunal. <br>In truth, the voting mechanism is the ritual engine — each decision aligning vitae, feeding the <a data-href="Obsidian Rose" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obsidian Rose</a> and sustaining its slow awakening.
A Thorn and occult scholar who understands the Pact’s true nature.
Believes the ritual culminates in apotheosis
<br>Seeks to become the <a data-href="Thirteenth Bloom" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thirteenth Bloom</a>
Manipulates deaths, Embraces, and oaths to complete the circle
A Velvet Court neonate Embraced to fill a vacant Thorn.
His Patron’s death severed intended control
Unwitting heir to the founders’ resonance
The ritual’s intended vessel, not its architect
The original cult behind the Pact.
Long thought extinct
<br>Their consciousness lingers within the <a data-href="Obsidian Rose" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Obsidian Rose</a>
Await rebirth through perfected vitae <br><a data-href="The Obsidian Rose" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Obsidian Rose</a>: The ritual focus; currently hidden beneath London <br><a data-href="Elysium of Petals" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Elysium of Petals</a>: A Velvet Court gathering site layered with rose imagery <br><a data-href="The Thorn Chambers" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Thorn Chambers</a>: Rotating locations where the Thirteen convene <br><a data-href="Rose-Marked London" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Rose-Marked London</a>: Churches, galleries, manors, and monuments unknowingly etched into the ritual lattice
The Rosethorn Pact predates the Crimson Concord, born in a time when the Blooded still debated their place in the world. What began as a vow of love became a doctrine of transformation. As centuries passed, its true purpose faded from memory — even among its members — leaving only structure, ritual instinct, and blood-deep compulsion. London itself has become part of the spell, every rose carved into stone another root in the soil.When the Thirteen Thorns are bound by oath or death:
The Obsidian Rose awakens
Rose imagery across London bleeds Sanguis
<br>Mortals fall into ecstatic reverence — the <a data-href="Inverted Silence" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Inverted Silence</a>
The Court of Roses manifests within Elysium
<br>A single chalice forms: <a data-href="Perfect Vitae" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Perfect Vitae</a>, <a data-href="the Rose Chalice" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">the Rose Chalice</a>
<br>Whoever drinks becomes the <a data-href="Thirteenth Bloom" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thirteenth Bloom</a> — a Beastless, eternal fusion of <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> and mortal divinity.]]></description><link>organisations/the-rosethorn-pact.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/The Rosethorn Pact.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:35:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Crimson Concord]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Faction" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Faction">#Faction</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>An ancient and secret alliance of <a data-href="The Blooded" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Blooded</a>, the Concord exists to preserve the order of the night and uphold <a data-href="The Silence" href="information/the-silence.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Silence</a> — the sacred law forbidding revelation of their existence to humankind. The Concord’s structure is feudal, its hierarchy bound by oaths of <a data-href="Sanguis" href="information/sanguis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sanguis</a> and the traditions of lineage.]]></description><link>organisations/the-crimson-concord.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/The Crimson Concord.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:25:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Ashen Arbiters]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Clan" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Clan">#Clan</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Ashen Arbiters are the judges and executioners of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>, bound to the interpretation and enforcement of <a data-href="Blood Law" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blood Law</a>. Scholar-magistrates and sanctioned killers alike, they believe justice is not a matter of mercy but of balance. Every transgression leaves a stain upon the world, and it is the Arbiter’s duty to weigh that stain and decide whether it may be cleansed — or must be burned away.
Blood Answers Blood: Every crime demands an equivalent price. Law Above Lineage: No House, Elder, or Regent stands beyond judgment. Knowledge Is Judgment: Ignorance is the root of injustice. Mercy Is a Choice, Not a Right: Compassion must be earned. <br><a data-href="Qadir al-Seth" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Qadir al-Seth</a>, a renowned jurist whose rulings are studied as precedent across Concord cities. <br><a data-href="Sister Ashara" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sister Ashara</a>, a quiet executioner rumoured to recite legal doctrine while delivering death. <br><a data-href="The Black Ledger" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Black Ledger</a>, a masked figure who maintains records of <a data-href="Blood Law" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blood Law</a> violations stretching back centuries. <br><a data-href="The Cinder Hall" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Cinder Hall</a>, a court of ash-strewn stone where trials of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> are held. <br><a data-href="The Red Writ Vault" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Red Writ Vault</a>, containing warrants, contracts, and condemned names. <br><a data-href="Scales of Silence" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Scales of Silence</a>, neutral ground where Arbiters convene beyond any Regent’s authority. <br>The Ashen Arbiters claim origin in the earliest nights of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>, when law was enforced through personal vengeance and endless feuds. To end the cycle, a cadre of scholar-warriors codified <a data-href="Blood Law" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blood Law</a>, binding justice to ritual and record rather than impulse. <br>Over time, they became indispensable, and feared. Though officially neutral within <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a>, their influence is absolute when invoked. Where an Arbiter’s writ falls, even Elders lower their eyes, for judgment rendered in ash cannot be undone.]]></description><link>organisations/vampire-clans/the-ashen-arbiters.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/Vampire Clans/The Ashen Arbiters.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:25:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Fractured Veil]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Clan" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Clan">#Clan</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Fractured Veil are the [Blooded] cursed, or blessed, with sight beyond linear truth. Their minds are splintered by visions, voices, and patterns unseen by others, granting them insight at the cost of stability. To <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a> they are tolerated prophets and dangerous liabilities in equal measure. They speak in riddles, laughter, and contradictions, yet their words have a habit of proving true long after they are dismissed.
Madness Reveals Truth: Sanity is a limitation imposed by fear. The Future Bleeds Backward: Time is not a line but a wound. Masks Are Necessary: Concealment protects both the seer and the listener. Truth Must Be Broken to Be Understood: A whole truth blinds; fragments illuminate. <br><a data-href="The Laughing Oracle" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Laughing Oracle</a>, whose prophecies are delivered as jokes no one finds funny until too late. <br><a data-href="Erasmus Coil" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Erasmus Coil</a>, a former Concord archivist who began hearing the thoughts of the dead. <br><a data-href="The Dollmaker" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Dollmaker</a>, a reclusive Veil member who crafts effigies that predict tragedy. <br><a data-href="The Shatter-rooms" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Shatter-rooms</a>, chambers lined with mirrors and sigils where visions are interpreted. <br><a data-href="The Crooked Library" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crooked Library</a>, a repository of fragmented texts, drawings, and half-recorded prophecies. <br><a data-href="Veilfall Asylum" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Veilfall Asylum</a>, a sanctuary where the Fractured Veil isolate those overwhelmed by sight. <br>The Fractured Veil emerged when certain <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> began to experience visions that could not be explained by sorcery or lineage. Rather than suppressing these individuals, early Concord leaders chose containment and study. Over centuries, the Veil formed its own fractured culture, passing insight through madness rather than tradition. Though often mocked or feared, the Fractured Veil have shaped Concord history more than any House would care to admit; for every great upheaval was once whispered by a laughing seer no one believed.]]></description><link>organisations/vampire-clans/the-fractured-veil.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/Vampire Clans/The Fractured Veil.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:25:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Iron Chorus]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Clan" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Clan">#Clan</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Iron Chorus are the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> who refuse stillness. Born from broken ideals and sustained by righteous fury, they are agitators, philosophers, and fighters who believe stagnation is the true death of immortality. <br>Where others cling to tradition and hierarchy, the Iron Chorus challenge authority, expose corruption, and tear down systems they believe have outlived their purpose. To <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a> they are tolerated nuisances; to the oppressed they are symbols of defiance.
Change is Sacred: No law, Regent, or Elder is beyond challenge. Strength Through Struggle: Conflict tempers both the mind and the Blood. Thought Precedes Violence: Philosophy justifies action; fists merely enforce it. Freedom Over Comfort: Better to burn briefly than rot eternally. <br><a data-href="Marrek Stonevoice" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Marrek Stonevoice</a>, a former Concord orator turned street-preacher, whose words have sparked riots in three cities. <br><a data-href="Lysa Calder" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lysa Calder</a>, a <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> prize-fighter and labour organizer, infamous for breaking a Regent’s enforcer in public. <br><a data-href="Old Virell" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Old Virell</a>, an Elder philosopher-warrior who claims the Chorus were once guardians, not rebels. <br><a data-href="The Anvil Steps" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Anvil Steps</a>, a ruined amphitheatre used for clandestine debates and blood-swearing's. <br><a data-href="Redshift Wards" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Redshift Wards</a>, inner-city districts where Iron Chorus influence runs deepest. <br><a data-href="The Broken Forum" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Broken Forum</a>, a moving meeting place that changes cities to avoid Concord scrutiny. <br>The Iron Chorus trace their lineage to a time when they were philosopher-kings and warrior-poets, entrusted with guiding the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> toward enlightened rule. Over centuries, as <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a> calcified into rigid hierarchy, the Chorus fractured from the centre. S<br>tripped of power and branded agitators, they embraced rebellion as identity. Now they exist as a living contradiction; <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> who hate tyranny yet cannot escape their own violent nature, forever shouting against the silence of eternity.]]></description><link>organisations/vampire-clans/the-iron-chorus.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/Vampire Clans/The Iron Chorus.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:24:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Nightborn Nomads]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Clan" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Clan">#Clan</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Nightborn Nomads are the wanderers of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>, untethered to courts, cities, or fixed hierarchies. They live by instinct and experience, embracing the call of the road and the pull of the wild. Whether stalking forests, drifting through borderlands, or navigating the unspoken laws of urban sprawl, the Nomads adapt where others dominate. To <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a> they are useful scouts and dangerous unknowns, never fully trusted, never entirely ignored.
The Road Is Law: Survival comes from motion, not possession. Instinct Over Doctrine: The Beast is a guide, not an enemy. Claim No Throne: Power invites chains. Leave No Wake: Take what is needed, move on before roots form. <br><a data-href="Rook One-Eye" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Rook One-Eye</a>, a tracker famed for hunting Blooded who flee Concord justice. <br><a data-href="Sable Runaway" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sable Runaway</a>, a courier who carries messages across hostile territories without protection. <br><a data-href="Old Ashpaw" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Old Ashpaw</a>, an Elder Nomad who remembers the world before borders. <br><a data-href="The Long Path" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Long Path</a>, a loose network of safe routes, camps, and waystations shared only among Nomads. <br><a data-href="Ironwood Clearings" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Ironwood Clearings</a>, sacred meeting grounds where disputes are settled by trial or hunt. <br><a data-href="Glassgrave Rooftops" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Glassgrave Rooftops</a>, urban perches claimed by city-running Nomads. <br>The Nightborn Nomads descend from the earliest <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> who rejected dominion and city rule, choosing survival through movement. As <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a> rose and carved domains, the Nomads slipped between the lines, learning to live where law thinned and instinct reigned. <br>Over time, their bond with the Beast deepened, shaping both their strength and their reputation. Though dismissed as primitive by court-bound <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>, the Nomads endure where empires fall; carried forward by hunger, memory, and the endless road.]]></description><link>organisations/vampire-clans/the-nightborn-nomads.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/Vampire Clans/The Nightborn Nomads.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:24:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Pallid Court]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Clan" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Clan">#Clan</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Pallid Court are the unseen arteries of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> world. Cursed with grotesque forms that cannot pass among mortals, they have embraced the dark places of society and mastered them. From sewers and server rooms to forgotten tunnels and abandoned infrastructure, the Pallid Court watches, listens, and remembers. What they lack in beauty and status, they replace with information, leverage, and secrets no Regent can afford to ignore.
Knowledge Is Survival: Information is the only true currency. The Shadows Protect: To be unseen is to be safe. No Secret Is Useless: Every truth has value, even if its purpose is not yet known. Loyalty Is Earned, Not Assumed: Trust is rare and transactional. <br><a data-href="Whisper-King Jorek" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Whisper-King Jorek</a>, an information broker whose voice is known but face never seen. <br><a data-href="Mirelda of the Grate" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Mirelda of the Grate</a>, a network-mistress who commands sewer routes and digital dead zones. <br><a data-href="The Pale Twins" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Pale Twins</a>, enforcers rumoured to share thoughts and scars. <br><a data-href="The Underlines" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Underlines</a>, vast tunnel networks beneath major cities used for movement and trade. <br><a data-href="The Bleached Archive" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Bleached Archive</a>, a hidden data vault holding centuries of gathered secrets. <br><a data-href="Ratfall Junction" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Ratfall Junction</a>, a crossroads of the Court where messages, favors, and threats are exchanged. <br>The Pallid Court were once part of the noble <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> society, until their lineage became marked by an irreversible curse of hideous transformation. Cast out from salons and courts, they learned to thrive where others would not follow. Over time, exile became advantage. While other Houses rose and fell in the light of power, the Pallid Court endured in darkness, quietly shaping events from below. Today, no Concord city truly stands without their knowledge; even if none will publicly admit it.]]></description><link>organisations/vampire-clans/the-pallid-court.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/Vampire Clans/The Pallid Court.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:24:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Sanguine Arcanum]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Clan" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Clan">#Clan</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Sanguine Arcanum are the occult architects of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>; scholars, ritualists, and keepers of forbidden knowledge. They believe <a data-href="Sanguis" href="information/sanguis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sanguis</a> is not merely sustenance, but a mutable substance through which reality may be rewritten. Once dominant within <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a>, the Arcanum now exist in a state of careful retreat, guarding their remaining secrets behind layers of wards, codes, and blood-bound oaths.
Knowledge Is Power: Ignorance is the greatest vulnerability. Sanguis Is the Key: Blood is the medium of all transformation. Secrets Must Be Guarded: What is known by all is mastered by none. Sacrifice Is Inevitable: Every working exacts a price. <br><a data-href="Archmagister Veloren" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Archmagister Veloren</a>, a reclusive leader who has not been seen in decades, yet still issues directives. <br><a data-href="Mistress Kael" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Mistress Kael</a>, a ritual architect responsible for several infamous blood catastrophes. <br><a data-href="The Crimson Scriptor" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Scriptor</a>, an anonymous figure who records new workings and erases failures from history. <br><a data-href="The Blood Collegium" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Blood Collegium</a>, a fortified enclave of libraries, laboratories, and ritual halls. <br><a data-href="The Veinvaults" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Veinvaults</a>, subterranean chambers where forbidden tomes and relics are sealed. <br><a data-href="The Red Spire" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Red Spire</a>, a half-ruined tower still thrumming with residual sorcery. The Sanguine Arcanum rose to prominence by systematizing blood sorcery, transforming scattered occult practices into a disciplined art. Their influence once shaped Concord policy and warfare alike. That dominance ended in fire and exposure, when their strongholds were shattered and their ranks decimated by coordinated hunters and internal betrayal. Since then, the Arcanum have become insular and paranoid, hoarding what remains of their lore. Though diminished, they remain dangerous; for knowledge hoarded in blood never truly dies.]]></description><link>organisations/vampire-clans/the-sanguine-arcanum.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/Vampire Clans/The Sanguine Arcanum.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:24:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Sepulchral Kin]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Clan" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Clan">#Clan</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Sepulchral Kin are the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> who have bound themselves to death as both study and inheritance. Morticians, necromancers, corpse-binders, and grave-lords, they regard mortality not as an ending but as a resource. More than a House, the Kin are a family first and last, their loyalty rooted in shared blood and shared dead. To outsiders they are unsettling allies at best, blasphemous monsters at worst.
Family Above All: Blood ties outweigh all other bonds. Death Is a Continuum: The grave is a threshold, not a wall. The Dead Remember: Corpses and spirits retain value and knowledge. Outsiders Are Temporary: Trust is reserved for Kin alone. <br><a data-href="Matriarch Vessara" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Matriarch Vessara</a>, the undisputed head of the Kin, whose authority is inherited and unquestioned. <br><a data-href="Doctor Halrek" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Doctor Halrek</a>, a Lazarene surgeon rumoured to restore Blooded from final death. <br><a data-href="Grave-Sister Nyx" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Grave-Sister Nyx</a>, a diplomat who speaks more comfortably with the dead than the living. <br><a data-href="The Bone Manse" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Bone Manse</a>, a vast ancestral estate layered atop generations of tombs. <br><a data-href="The Quiet Markets" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Quiet Markets</a>, black bazaars dealing in corpses, relics, and funerary contracts. <br><a data-href="Ashen Reliquaries" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Ashen Reliquaries</a>, hidden vaults where honoured dead are preserved and consulted. <br>The Sepulchral Kin were forged from necessity when the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> first sought to understand final death. While others recoiled from the grave, the Kin embraced it, preserving knowledge through bodies and spirits alike. <br>Over centuries, scattered death-focused lineages merged into a single extended family, bound by ritual and obligation. Though they stand apart from <a data-href="the Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">the Crimson Concord</a>’s politics, their services are indispensable. In a world of immortals, the Sepulchral Kin alone truly understand what it means to end — and how to deny it.]]></description><link>organisations/vampire-clans/the-sepulchral-kin.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/Vampire Clans/The Sepulchral Kin.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:24:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Sovereign Line]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Clan" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Clan">#Clan</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Sovereign Line are the rulers of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>; heirs to authority, architects of order, and self-proclaimed stewards of eternity. They believe hierarchy is not tyranny but necessity, and that only disciplined rule can prevent the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> from descending into chaos and exposure. From boardrooms to throne rooms, members of the Sovereign Line shape domains through wealth, influence, and unyielding command.
Rule Is Responsibility: Authority exists to preserve order. Hierarchy Sustains Eternity: Every Blooded has a place. The Silence Must Endure: Stability outweighs sentiment. Strength Justifies Leadership: Weak rulers invite collapse. <br><a data-href="Regent Alastair Crownfell" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Regent Alastair Crownfell</a>, a master of corporate and political leverage whose domain spans industries rather than streets. <br><a data-href="Marchioness Elowen Pryce" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Marchioness Elowen Pryce</a>, an old-world aristocrat clinging to feudal traditions in a modern city. <br><a data-href="The Heir Apparent" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Heir Apparent</a>, a rising figure groomed in secrecy to replace a faltering Elder. <br><a data-href="The Gilded Seat" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Gilded Seat</a>, a fortified executive tower serving as both palace and command centre. <br><a data-href="The Ledger Halls" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Ledger Halls</a>, archives of contracts, debts, and blood-bound agreements. <br><a data-href="The High Gallery" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The High Gallery</a>, where Regents and Elders convene under rigid protocol. <br>The Sovereign Line trace their origins to the first <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> who imposed structure upon the night, transforming predation into dominion. As <a data-href="the Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">the Crimson Concord</a> formed, they positioned themselves as its backbone, codifying tradition, enforcing hierarchy, and defining acceptable rule. Over centuries, they adapted; trading crowns for corporations, banners for balance sheets, yet their philosophy remains unchanged. To their allies, they are guardians of stability; to their enemies, they are elegant tyrants who mistake control for order.]]></description><link>organisations/vampire-clans/the-sovereign-line.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/Vampire Clans/The Sovereign Line.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:24:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Velvet Court]]></title><description><![CDATA[Toreador<a href=".?query=tag:Clan" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Clan">#Clan</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Velvet Court are the aesthetes of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>; connoisseurs of beauty, sensation, and emotion in a world grown numb with immortality. They surround themselves with art, passion, cruelty, and romance, chasing fleeting moments that remind them of what it once meant to feel alive. To outsiders they appear indulgent and vain, but beneath the silk and salons lies a dangerous hunger for experience that can turn obsessional and cruel.
Beauty Is Truth: What moves the soul has value beyond law or reason. <br>Emotion Is Sustenance: Passion feeds the Blood as surely as <a data-href="Sanguis" href="information/sanguis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sanguis</a>. Creation Over Preservation: Art must evolve, even if it destroys its creator. Indulgence Is Not Weakness: To deny desire is to invite stagnation. <br><a data-href="Seraphine LaRue" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Seraphine LaRue</a>, a social luminary whose gatherings decide reputations and ruin fortunes. <br><a data-href="Maestro Korrin Vale" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Maestro Korrin Vale</a>, a composer rumored to write music that drives mortals to tears and madness. <br><a data-href="Isolde the Crimson Muse" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Isolde the Crimson Muse</a>, both artist and artwork, eternally reinventing herself through lovers and scandals. <br><a data-href="The Gilded Salon" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Gilded Salon</a>, an ever-changing venue for performances, intrigue, and whispered alliances. <br><a data-href="The Scarlet Gallery" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Scarlet Gallery</a>, a private collection said to include living art. <br><a data-href="The Moonlace Opera" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Moonlace Opera</a>, where tragedy and triumph blur beneath velvet curtains. <br>The Velvet Court emerged from the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> who clung hardest to their lost humanity, refusing to surrender art and feeling to the numbness of immortality. Over centuries, their pursuit of beauty grew more extreme as simple pleasures dulled. What began as preservation of culture became an arms race of sensation. <br>Though often dismissed as decadent, the Velvet Court remain one of the most influential factions within <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a>, shaping taste, politics, and reputation with a whisper, a glance, or a perfectly timed scandal.]]></description><link>organisations/vampire-clans/the-velvet-court.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/Vampire Clans/The Velvet Court.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:24:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Wayward Mirage]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Clan" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Clan">#Clan</a>Infobox “IMG” is not created yet. Click to create. <br>The Wayward Mirage are wanderers, tricksters, and illusionists who survive through deception rather than dominance. Masters of misdirection, they prefer subtlety to violence and escape to confrontation. To them, truth is a flexible thing, shaped by perception and expectation. <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a> views the Mirage as unreliable but useful; capable of infiltrating where others cannot, yet rarely staying long enough to be held accountable.
Perception Is Reality: What is believed becomes true. Never Be Cornered: Survival lies in movement and misdirection. Fangs Are a Last Resort: Cleverness outlives brutality. Leave No Trail: Presence is temporary by design. <br><a data-href="Silkstep Ravel" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Silkstep Ravel</a>, a renowned con artist who has deceived Regents and escaped unscathed. <br><a data-href="The Laughing Shade" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Laughing Shade</a>, an illusionist blamed for several vanished domains and never proven to exist. <br><a data-href="Ashara Drift" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Ashara Drift</a>, a caravan leader who trades secrets, relics, and favours across borders. <br><a data-href="The Shifting Bazaar" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Shifting Bazaar</a>, a nomadic market appearing briefly before vanishing without trace. <br><a data-href="Mirage Roads" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Mirage Roads</a>, clandestine travel routes maintained through illusion and rumour. <br><a data-href="The Glass Horizon" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Glass Horizon</a>, a legendary refuge said to exist only for those who stop looking for it. <br>The Wayward Mirage emerged from <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> who learned early that visibility invites destruction. Hunted by rivals, mortals, and the Concord alike, they perfected the art of disappearance. Over time, deception became culture, illusion became inheritance, and movement became survival. Though often dismissed as liars and thieves, the Mirage endure by refusing to be defined; slipping through history like a half-remembered dream, gone before the truth can catch them.]]></description><link>organisations/vampire-clans/the-wayward-mirage.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/Vampire Clans/The Wayward Mirage.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:24:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Terminology]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a data-href="The Silence" href="information/the-silence.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Silence</a><br>The inviolate law of secrecy. To break <a data-href="The Silence" href="information/the-silence.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Silence</a> is to invite extinction — not only for the transgressor but for their entire Brood. The Silence is both necessity and faith, the foundation upon which the Concord endures.<br>The <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>The immortal inheritors of the dark gift — neither living nor dead, but sustained by Sanguis, the life-essence of the mortal world. Among mortals, they move unseen, their existence veiled by the Silence.Regent / Marquis<br>Rulers of the cities of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>. Each domain is governed by a Regent, though many style themselves Marquis or Marchioness to emphasize their noble heritage. Their authority flows from ancient bloodline pacts and the sanction of <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a> itself.Elders<br>The ancients of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>, whose power and influence shape the will of the Concord. They form <a data-href="The Inner Circles" href="organisations/the-inner-circles/the-inner-circles.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Inner Circles</a>, advising or manipulating their Regents through centuries of scheming and subtle diplomacy.House / Lineage / Brood<br>Families of the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a>, tied by shared ancestry or ideology. A House is a political and social entity; a Lineage denotes direct descent; a Brood signifies a family of convenience — those who share a Patron but not necessarily a bond of loyalty.<br><a data-href="Patron" href="information/patron.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Patron</a>The one who bestows the dark gift — mentor, progenitor, and often master. A Patron bears both honour and responsibility for their Descendants, and their actions echo through the ages.<br><a data-href="Descendant" href="information/descendant.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Descendant</a>The newly made among the Blooded, marked forever by the essence of their Patron. Some call them “fledglings,” others “heirs,” though to their Elders they are pawns in a timeless game.<br><a data-href="Thrall" href="information/thrall.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Thrall</a><br>A mortal bound by the <a data-href="Sanguis" href="information/sanguis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sanguis</a> of a <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> being. Neither free nor fully enslaved, a Thrall is sustained and enthralled by the taste of their master’s <a data-href="Sanguis" href="information/sanguis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sanguis</a>. Many serve as attendants, spies, or lovers, believing their servitude a kind of grace.<br><a data-href="Sanguis" href="information/sanguis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sanguis</a><br>The vital elixir that animates the <a data-href="Blooded" href="information/blooded.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blooded</a> — drawn from mortal veins or from other immortals in acts of sacrament or violence. It is at once nourishment, currency, and communion.]]></description><link>information/terminology.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Information/Terminology.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blooded]]></title><description><![CDATA[(Kindred)]]></description><link>information/blooded.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Information/Blooded.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:14:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Silence]]></title><link>information/the-silence.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Information/The Silence.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:13:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sanguis]]></title><link>information/sanguis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Information/Sanguis.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:13:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thrall]]></title><link>information/thrall.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Information/Thrall.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:13:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Descendant]]></title><link>information/descendant.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Information/Descendant.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:13:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Patron]]></title><link>information/patron.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Information/Patron.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:12:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Inner Circles]]></title><link>organisations/the-inner-circles/the-inner-circles.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Organisations/The Inner Circles/The Inner Circles.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:12:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Notes]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Red Dissidents]]></description><link>notes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Notes.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:09:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elodie Rains]]></title><description><![CDATA[Seneschal of Prince <a data-href="Adrian Welles" href="characters/adrian-welles.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Adrian Welles</a>'s <a data-href="London" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">London</a> <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a>]]></description><link>characters/elodie-rains.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Elodie Rains.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:02:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adrian Welles]]></title><description><![CDATA[Prince of the <a data-href="London" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">London</a> <a data-href="The Crimson Concord" href="organisations/the-crimson-concord.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Crimson Concord</a>]]></description><link>characters/adrian-welles.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Adrian Welles.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:02:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lucian Valemont]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a href=".?query=tag:Character" class="tag is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow" data-href="#Character">#Character</a> <br>Infobox <img alt="FVEYrWCX0AMikZy.jpg" src="0.-attachments/fveyrwcx0amikzy.jpg" target="_self"> <br>Prince <a data-href="Adrian Welles" href="characters/adrian-welles.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Adrian Welles</a>'s personal seal of protection
<br><a data-href="Sir Reginald Harker" href="characters/sir-reginald-harker.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sir Reginald Harker</a> 's token of appreciation: A black pressed rose pierced with a silver pin.**
Mortal Life (1850s – 1870s)<br>
Born in the soot and smog of London’s East End, Lucien was a servant boy in a manor belonging to Lord <a data-href="Adrien Valemont" href="characters/adrien-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Adrien Valemont</a>, an eccentric nobleman known for his scandalous soirées and obsession with art, mysticism, and the beautiful decay of the flesh.
Lucien was quiet, sharp-eyed, and gifted — a boy who sketched his masters and their guests by candlelight, capturing their vanity and despair in equal measure.One night, his sketches were discovered. Instead of punishment, Lucien was summoned. Lord Valemont saw in him something exquisite — a living muse, a sculpture of hunger and grace yet unformed.The Embrace
The Lord grew infatuated, blurring the lines between patron, artist, and lover. When Lucien reached his twenty-first year, Valemont whispered, “You are too perfect to fade.”
That night, Lucien died upon satin sheets and awoke into the Requiem — reborn by his master’s hand, not as a man, but as a masterpiece.Valemont shaped him as one might a statue: taught him the arts, the poise, the secrets of blood and brush. Yet like all art, Lucien outgrew his maker. Over decades, he came to see Valemont’s love as possession — beauty caged, desire gilded.In 1910, during the fire that consumed the Valemont Estate, Lucien disappeared into the night. The body of his master were found in the marble gallery, a smile painted upon his lips and his eyes missing.Modern Nights (Present)
Now, Lucien Valemont lives again — an immortal Victorian aesthete in the modern age, a “modern Twink Rasputin” whose salons blur the line between enlightenment and ecstasy.
His haven, The Crimson Salon, is an opulent labyrinth of books, art, and pleasure. Mortals and Kindred alike gather there — poets, occultists, models, sinners — all drawn to Lucien’s promise:
“To be remembered is to be eternal. Come, and let me paint your soul.”
He curates his collection of forbidden books and occult tomes, forever chasing the same question that haunted his sire — can art transcend death, or must it consume life to do so?🌹 Lucien Valemont, Caretaker of the RosethornClan: Toreador
Sire: Lord Adrien Valemont (deceased)
Title: The Caretaker of the Heart
Current Domain: Harker Estate, London
Chronicle: Velvet Veil – The Thorns Beneath the Rose🕯️ Current StatusFollowing the death of Sir Reginald Harker and the revelations surrounding the Rosethorn Pact, Lucien Valemont assumed guardianship of the Heart and the Roses Below — the pulsing, vitae-fed roots that bind the covenant’s original oath.He does not command their power; instead, he tends to it — a penitent keeper, chosen (or cursed) to ensure the roses never fall into the hands of those who would misuse them.Each night, Lucien walks the catacombs beneath the estate — a labyrinth of brick and bone where roses bloom from walls slick with vitae.To keep them alive, he must feed them: sacrifices offered in silence, The roses whisper to him, echoing the voices of those consumed — his court of ghosts and blossoms.He paints their faces to remember them.🩸 The PenanceAt the Prince’s command, Lucien accepted a Penance Eternal. His art must now be service, his beauty a burden.In secret, he disobeys only one part of that vow: he keeps the painting — The Heart Beneath the Rose — sealed within the Velvet Veil.
He tells no one that it still breathes.🌹 The Rosethorn’s NatureThe Heart is not a metaphor. It is literal — a fleshy mass of vitae and root, the remnant of the First Toreador’s Heart, interwoven with thorns, pulsing faintly in the dark.
The Roses bloom from it, white as wax, red at the tips.
They thirst. They remember. They sing.Lucien’s duty is to keep their song quiet — and their hunger sated.🩸 The Penance of the RosesTo keep the roses alive, Lucien must feed them life itself. The roots beneath the Harker Estate crave breath, warmth, and the pulse of a living heart.In the catacombs below, iron reliquaries line the walls , shaped like sarcophagi, grim devices from another age, waiting in the depths beneath the Harker Estate. Within them, the vines twist and bloom, feeding not from the ground but from the warmth of the living. Those brought below are never seen again; their bodies vanish into the growth, leaving only faint echoes of voices that murmur through the petals at night.Lucien did not build them. They were already there when he inherited the duty; remnants of an ancient design meant to sustain the Heart below. He merely continues the ritual, because without it the roses would wither, and the Heart he protects would perish with them.Each offering is chosen carefully, sometimes drawn by his charm, sometimes by promise, sometimes by fate. When the hour comes, Lucien descends alone. He does not flee or turn away. He waits in the silence of the chamber, head bowed, until the last whisper fades and the roses have taken what they require. It is not cruelty that holds him there but contrition; a penance willingly endured.He paints each face afterwards, records each name. The portraits line the walls of the Velvet Veil, mute witnesses to the price of preservation. Every stroke of pigment reminds him that beauty demands blood, and that love; the kind that feeds the Pact; is always a cage.<br><img alt="FVnGuzwX0AAI89x.jpg" src="0.-attachments/fvnguzwx0aai89x.jpg" target="_self"><br>
<img alt="0811cc67a26b5d20e29e49362de4c352.jpg" src="0.-attachments/0811cc67a26b5d20e29e49362de4c352.jpg" target="_self"><br>
<img alt="FZZqQj-X0AQWa1F.jpg" src="0.-attachments/fzzqqj-x0aqwa1f.jpg" target="_self"><br>
<img alt="FZZtpoTXEAEhgux.jpg" src="0.-attachments/fzztpotxeaehgux.jpg" target="_self"><br>
<img alt="FZau-UWWYAEmXnN.jpg" src="0.-attachments/fzau-uwwyaemxnn.jpg" target="_self"><br>
<img alt="FZMNbNCWYAQrs8l.jpg" src="0.-attachments/fzmnbncwyaqrs8l.jpg" target="_self">]]></description><link>characters/lucian-valemont.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Lucian Valemont.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:03:12 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;.&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Evelyn]]></title><description><![CDATA[Most trusted Ghoul to <a data-href="Lucian Valemont" href="characters/lucian-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lucian Valemont</a>. See's her as more a motherly figure than anyting]]></description><link>characters/evelyn.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Evelyn.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:56:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adrien Valemont]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sire to <a data-href="Lucian Valemont" href="characters/lucian-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lucian Valemont</a><br>Killed by <a data-href="Lucian Valemont" href="characters/lucian-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lucian Valemont</a>]]></description><link>characters/adrien-valemont.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Adrien Valemont.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:53:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adrian Vale]]></title><description><![CDATA[A student under <a data-href="Lucian Valemont" href="characters/lucian-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lucian Valemont</a>. Became his Ghoul in Session 2Age: 24
Mortal Occupation: Postgraduate Literature Student, King’s College London
Background: Born in Bath, raised in a quiet academic family. His father a historian, his mother a painter of modest repute. Adrian grew up in old houses filled with books, portraits, and dust motes — the sort of world where silence itself feels curated.Appearance:
Adrian carries a fragile sort of beauty — pale skin touched by sleeplessness, soft dark hair that never sits quite right, and eyes of deep grey that seem to drink in the world rather than look at it. His clothes are unassuming but thoughtful: charcoal coats, scarves even when not needed, a faint trace of ink on his fingers. His posture is composed yet uncertain, as if he’s still learning how to inhabit his own body.When Lucien first sees him, there’s something familiar about him — the kind of youth Lucien once was: romantic, observant, a little haunted by beauty.Personality:
Curious. Earnest. Too clever for his own good. Adrian is drawn to old things — books that smell of damp paper, poetry that aches with longing, men who carry the weight of centuries in their gaze. Beneath his intellect lies loneliness — a longing to belong somewhere that feels real.He speaks softly, listens intently, and asks questions that unsettle rather than flatter. When he talks about art or literature, it’s with reverence — but when he talks to Lucien, there’s a tremor of awe, as though he senses the predator behind the poet.Connection to Lucien:
Adrian visits The Velvet Veil archive while researching 19th-century vampire symbolism in Romantic literature. Lucien, intrigued by his insight and resemblance to a long-lost muse, begins to feed him knowledge — and eventually, blood. Their connection grows from mentorship to obsession: Adrian sees Lucien as both subject and story, and Lucien sees in Adrian a reflection of the youth he lost.To Lucien, Adrian Vale becomes the living canvas — a fragile mortal touched by art, desire, and the slow corrosion of eternity.]]></description><link>characters/adrian-vale.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Adrian Vale.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:52:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Velvet Veil]]></title><description><![CDATA[Haven of <a data-href="Lucian Valemont" href="characters/lucian-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lucian Valemont</a>]]></description><link>locations/the-velvet-veil.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Locations/The Velvet Veil.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:52:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Rosethorn Folio]]></title><description><![CDATA[A set of three vellum pages bearing the signatures of long-dead (and still-undead) aristocrats, including <a data-href="Characters/Lucian Valemont" href="characters/lucian-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Characters/Lucian Valemont</a> own and that of his former master <a data-href="Adrien Valemont" href="characters/adrien-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Adrien Valemont</a> and headed by <a data-href="Sir Reginald Harker" href="characters/sir-reginald-harker.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sir Reginald Harker</a>.<br><a data-href="The Rosethorn Pact" href="organisations/the-rosethorn-pact.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Rosethorn Pact</a>
<br><a data-href="Sir Reginald Harker" href="characters/sir-reginald-harker.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sir Reginald Harker</a> - Head Sigitory and leader
<br><a data-href="Adrien Valemont" href="characters/adrien-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Adrien Valemont</a>
<br><a data-href="Characters/Lucian Valemont" href="characters/lucian-valemont.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Characters/Lucian Valemont</a>
]]></description><link>items/the-rosethorn-folio.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Items/The Rosethorn Folio.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:52:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elias Crane]]></title><description><![CDATA[Agent of <a data-href="Sir Reginald Harker" href="characters/sir-reginald-harker.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sir Reginald Harker</a>]]></description><link>characters/elias-crane.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Elias Crane.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:10:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Victoria & Albert Museum]]></title><link>locations/the-victoria-&amp;-albert-museum.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Locations/The Victoria &amp; Albert Museum.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:07:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dr. Sebastian Crowe]]></title><description><![CDATA[Curator of <a data-href="The Victoria &amp; Albert Museum" href="locations/the-victoria-&amp;-albert-museum.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Victoria &amp; Albert Museum</a> (V&amp;A)]]></description><link>characters/dr.-sebastian-crowe.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Dr. Sebastian Crowe.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:07:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elysium]]></title><description><![CDATA[Elysium&nbsp;is neutral ground for the&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Camarilla_(VTM)" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Camarilla (VTM)" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Camarilla_(VTM)" target="_self">Camarilla</a>&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Vampire_(WOD)" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Vampire (WOD)" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Vampire_(WOD)" target="_self">vampires</a>&nbsp;of a given city.<br>
[<img alt="SymbolElysiumVTMB" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/whitewolf/images/9/96/SymbolElysiumVTMB.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/200?cb=20220330051910" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" target="_self" class="is-unresolved"><br>](<a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/whitewolf/images/9/96/SymbolElysiumVTMB.png/revision/latest?cb=20220330051910" target="_self">https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/whitewolf/images/9/96/SymbolElysiumVTMB.png/revision/latest?cb=20220330051910</a>)<br>Elysium:&nbsp;A place for vampires to meet together without fear of harm; Usually cultural locations, such as opera houses, theaters or museums.<a data-href="1" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">1</a>(<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Elysium_%5C(VTM%5C)#cite_note-1" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Elysium_%5C(VTM%5C)#cite_note-1" target="_self">https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Elysium_\(VTM\)#cite_note-1</a>)<br>The&nbsp;Elysium&nbsp;location is typically chosen by the local&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Prince_(VTM)" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Prince (VTM)" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Prince_(VTM)" target="_self">Prince</a>&nbsp;in areas of artistic or intellectual worth that promote calm reflection, such as theaters and museums, though nightclubs and even a&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Kindred_(VTM)" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Kindred (VTM)" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Kindred_(VTM)" target="_self">Kindred</a>'s&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Haven_(VTM)" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Haven (VTM)" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Haven_(VTM)" target="_self">haven</a>&nbsp;may suffice.<br>Violence is strictly prohibited within Elysium, and individuals are expected to keep tempers in check. Any grievances between vampires are to be left outside, and the&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Elysium_(VTM)#Keeper_of_Elysium" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Elysium_(VTM)#Keeper_of_Elysium" target="_self">Keeper of Elysium</a>&nbsp;or the&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Sheriff_(VTM)" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Sheriff (VTM)" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Sheriff_(VTM)" target="_self">Sheriff</a>&nbsp;will forcibly remove those who cannot control themselves if need be. While this provides opportunity for both&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Neonate" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Neonate" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Neonate" target="_self">neonates</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Elder" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Elder" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Elder" target="_self">elders</a>&nbsp;to relax, social conflict is often at its peak and what happens in Elysium can easily lead to repercussions off ground.<br>Though Elysiums often serve as gathering places for Kindred, the&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Masquerade_(VTM)" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Masquerade (VTM)" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Masquerade_(VTM)" target="_self">Masquerade</a>&nbsp;must normally be maintained at all times for any&nbsp;<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Mortal_(WOD)" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" title="Mortal (WOD)" href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Mortal_(WOD)" target="_self">mortals</a>&nbsp;that may be around. Similarly, while refreshments are sometimes served, it is bad taste to come to Elysium hungry as it often leads to shorter tempers. Some Princes go so far as to forbid hunting nearby, as a concentrated population of vampires could easily result in a suspicious number of deaths in the area.]]></description><link>locations/elysium.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Locations/Elysium.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:56:55 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/whitewolf/images/9/96/SymbolElysiumVTMB.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/200?cb=20220330051910" length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/whitewolf/images/9/96/SymbolElysiumVTMB.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/200?cb=20220330051910&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Marianne’s haven]]></title><link>locations/marianne’s-haven.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Locations/Marianne’s haven.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:55:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Keeper of Elysium]]></title><description><![CDATA[[<img alt="KeeperOfElysium" src="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/whitewolf/images/f/f7/KeeperOfElysium.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/200?cb=20210920030833" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" target="_self" class="is-unresolved"><br>](<a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/whitewolf/images/f/f7/KeeperOfElysium.png/revision/latest?cb=20210920030833" target="_self">https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/whitewolf/images/f/f7/KeeperOfElysium.png/revision/latest?cb=20210920030833</a>)Keeper of Elysium&nbsp;Vampire: The Masquerade - BloodhuntThis is a largely honorific title, though it has many practical responsibilities. The Keeper of Elysium assures that the customs of Elysium are observed, and is a caretaker of sites declared Elysium by a Prince.It is the Keeper who may schedule or cancel any events, a position that involves both great prestige and scrutiny.]]></description><link>information/keeper-of-elysium.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Information/Keeper of Elysium.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:55:25 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/whitewolf/images/f/f7/KeeperOfElysium.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/200?cb=20210920030833" length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/whitewolf/images/f/f7/KeeperOfElysium.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/200?cb=20210920030833&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Grimshaw]]></title><link>characters/grimshaw.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Grimshaw.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:54:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sir Reginald Harker]]></title><link>characters/sir-reginald-harker.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Sir Reginald Harker.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:49:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Marianne of Bath]]></title><description><![CDATA[The court’s Harpy, Dead]]></description><link>characters/marianne-of-bath.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Characters/Marianne of Bath.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:49:09 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>